<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-05-10T15:25:42+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Autism Education</title><subtitle>Autism Games, Autism Intervention and Autism Education</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Autism And Diffuse Developmental Disorders</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/autism-and-diffuse-developmental-disorders/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Autism And Diffuse Developmental Disorders" /><published>2018-10-04T06:39:18+03:00</published><updated>2018-10-04T06:39:18+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/autism-and-diffuse-developmental-disorders</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/autism-and-diffuse-developmental-disorders/">&lt;p&gt;A violation of mental development, which is characterized by motor and speech disorders and leads to a violation of social interaction, is autism. This disease has a strong influence on the child’s previous development and on the whole life of the person in the future. There are no medical tests that could diagnose autism. Only by observing the behavior of the child and his communication with others can diagnose “autism.”
&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2018/10/autism--1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;autism--1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Include a group of disorders characterized by qualitative anomalies in social communication and a limited, stereotyped, repetitive set of interests and actions. In most cases, development is disrupted from infancy, always in the first 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some cases, the disorders are combined and presumably due to congenital rubella, tuberous sclerosis, cerebral lipidosis, X-chromosome fragility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The onset of the disorder is at the age of 2.5-3 years, sometimes after a period of normal development in early childhood. Usually these are beautiful children with a pensive, sleepy, detached face - a “prince’s face”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Autistic loneliness - inability to establish a warm emotional relationship with people. Such children do not respond with a smile to affection and manifestations of the love of their parents. They do not like being taken or hugged. They react to their parents no more than to other people. Equally behave with people and inanimate objects. Almost no alarms are detected when separated from loved ones and in unfamiliar surroundings. Typical is the absence of eye contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disorder of speech skills. Speech often develops with a delay or does not arise at all. Sometimes it develops normally until the age of 2 years, and then partially disappears. Autistic children use little of the category of “values” in memory and thinking. Some children make noise (clicks, sounds, wheezes, meaningless syllables) in a stereotyped manner with no desire to communicate. Speech is usually constructed by the type of immediate or delayed echolalia or in the form of stereotyped phrases outside the context, with the misuse of pronouns. Even by 5-6 years, most children call themselves in the second or third person or by name, not using the “I”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An obsession with monotony. Stereotyped and ritual behavior, insisting on keeping everything unchanged and resisting change. They prefer to eat the same food, wear the same clothes, play repetitive games. The activity and play of autistic children are characterized by rigidity, repetition and monotony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typical also bizarre behavior and mannerisms (for example, the child is constantly spinning or swinging, fingering his fingers or clapping his hands).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deviations in the game. Games are more often stereotyped, not functional and not social. Most atypical manipulation of toys, there is no imagination and symbolic features. There is a passion for games with unstructured material - sand, water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atypical sensory reactions. Autistic children respond to sensory stimuli either extremely strongly, or too weakly (for sounds, pain). They selectively ignore the speech addressed to them, showing interest in non-verbal, more often mechanical sounds. The pain threshold is often lowered, or an atypical reaction to pain is noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With children’s autism, there may be other signs. Sudden flashes of anger, or irritation, or fear, not caused by any obvious cause. Sometimes these children are either hyperactive or confused. Behavior with self-harm in the form of head blows, biting, scratching, pulling out the hair. Sometimes there are violations of sleep, enuresis, encopresis, eating problems. In 25% of cases there may be convulsive seizures in pre-pubertal or puberty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diagnosis of Autism&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doctors are not immediately able to identify autism in a child. The reason for this is that such symptoms of autism are also observed with the normal development of the child. Because of this, the diagnosis is often delayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If parents found the child’s symptoms of autism, they should immediately contact a child psychiatrist. Currently, many child development centers have been established, which will help diagnose and provide effective assistance in treatment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="autism-diagnosis" /><summary type="html">A violation of mental development, which is characterized by motor and speech disorders and leads to a violation of social interaction, is autism. This disease has a strong influence on the child’s previous development and on the whole life of the person in the future. There are no medical tests that could diagnose autism. Only by observing the behavior of the child and his communication with others can diagnose “autism.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Easiest Method Of Diagnosing Autism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-easiest-method-of-diagnosing-autism/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Easiest Method Of Diagnosing Autism" /><published>2018-10-03T08:30:35+03:00</published><updated>2018-10-03T08:30:35+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the-easiest-method-of-diagnosing-autism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-easiest-method-of-diagnosing-autism/">&lt;p&gt;What Is Autism?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To date, children’s autism is seen as a common developmental disorder. That is, it is not really a disease, but it is a serious violation of mental development. A child with autism spectrum disorder (ADS) needs special attention of doctors, educators, psychologists and, of course, parents.
&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2018/10/autism.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;autism&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How To Diagnose Autism?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several types of autism spectrum disorders. According to the international classification of diseases ICD-10, four types are distinguished:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Children’s autism (autistic disorder, infantile autism, infantile psychosis, Kanner’s syndrome);&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Atypical autism;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Rett syndrome;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Asperger syndrome, autistic psychopathy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, all autistic disorders began to be combined under the general abbreviation of ADS - autism spectrum disorder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Are The Symptoms of Canner’s Syndrome?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Symptoms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) impossibility to establish full contact with people from the beginning of life;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) extreme isolation from the outside world;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) ignoring external and internal stimuli, until they become painful;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) inadequate use of the communicative function of speech;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) absence or insufficiency of eye contact;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) fear of changes in the environment;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7) immediate and delayed echolalia (uncontrolled automatic repetition of words and phrases after other people);&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8) stereotyped and impulsive behavior and manipulative games;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9) development delay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2018/10/autism-child.png&quot; alt=&quot;autism-child&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Are The Symptoms Of Asperger’s Syndrome?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the symptoms are similar to Kanner’s syndrome: communicative disorders and a stereotyped range of interests, a weak reaction to external stimuli. The following attributes are added:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Contrasting desires and representations;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Often - the ability to an unusual, non-standard understanding of oneself and others;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Saved or even well-developed logical thinking with unstable attention;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Delay of speech and cognitive development, as a rule, is absent;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) Speech - peculiar in melody, rhythm and tempo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) A rejected, diffused view, a scant facial expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Symptoms Of Rett Syndrome&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It appears at the age of 8-30 months without any external causes. This is the most serious violation among the ADS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) It appears against the background of normal motor development;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Gradually lost already acquired skills, including speech;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Violent movements of “washing type” in the hands;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) Loss of ability to hold objects, dystonia, muscle atrophies, kyphosis, scoliosis and etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the progressive disease and total disintegration of all spheres of life, the child usually retains emotional adequacy and affection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Symptoms Of Atypical Autism&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A disorder similar to Kanner’s syndrome, but at least one of the mandatory diagnostic criteria is absent. Often one or another sign of impaired development manifests itself in a child after the age of 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which Doctor Can Diagnose A Child Autism?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the International Classification of Diseases, autistic disorders are included in the section “Mental and behavioral disorders”, therefore the leading role in the diagnosis and formation of a treatment-corrective program belongs to a psychiatrist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the clinical picture of the child’s condition is not clear enough, the psychiatrist diagnoses “Autistic behavior”. This means: we have little information, but the behavior of the child is very similar in symptoms to autism. This diagnosis requires further clarification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Are The Differences Of A Child With Autism?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its most general form, autism is characterized by a delay in development and reluctance to contact other people. It is important to understand that this disorder has many manifestations: in the development of motor skills, speech, attention, perception. A child with autism can be recognized by such particular signs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The child does not seek contact with other people, does not react to them, as if he does not notice;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He often makes the same repetitive movements: shakes his hands, bounces, performs complex rituals (repetitive actions);&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The circle of his interests is limited, it is difficult for him to get carried away with something new;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The behavior of the child is often destructive: it is aggressive, can scream, cause damage to itself, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="autism-diagnosis" /><summary type="html">What Is Autism?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Everyday Life Of An Autistic</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/everyday-life-of-an-autistic/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Everyday Life Of An Autistic" /><published>2018-10-02T08:03:44+03:00</published><updated>2018-10-02T08:03:44+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/everyday-life-of-an-autistic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/everyday-life-of-an-autistic/">&lt;p&gt;Autism is a relatively new disorder, which is becoming more common. Its exact causes and methods of treatment are still a mystery. Experts believe that autism is the result of neurological disorders that affect the functioning of the brain, development, communication and social interaction skills. In other words, it is a disease of the nervous system.
&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2018/10/autism-.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;autism-&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Problems People With Autism Have?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People with autism have problems in communicating and understanding other people and what is happening. The ability to instinctively sympathize with others is much weaker than that of ordinary people. This is the main reason why they often look insensitive. They find it hard to understand jokes and sarcasm. Sometimes they take the settled expressions literally. Some people with autism are also finding hard time to talk. They often just repeat what they heard (echolalia).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing Things Not Accepted In Society&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are poorly versed in generally accepted rules and local etiquette. They can do things that are not accepted in society. For example, a long time to stand in front of a mirror in a store or approach a person too close. Autism deprives them of the concept of the dangers of certain actions. It is also difficult for them to predict the results of some actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding The World Around&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For people with autism, the world seems to be a chaos, in which it is very difficult to understand. Therefore, they are afraid of him and try to less contact with others. Due to the fact that the world becomes unpredictable, the only way out is routine. People with autism often repeat the same movements or actions. For example, a child with autism can for ten minutes (or even more) jump from one corner of the room to another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changes Lead To Bad Feelings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new event that interrupts a worked out mechanism can lead to a general malfunction. Even the idea of change itself can lead to bad feelings. For example, if a person with autism walks on the same road to the store, then the blocked road can put him in a dead end, and he just returns back home.
&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2018/10/Autism--.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Autism--&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loud Sounds Are Distracting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A person with autism, as a rule, finds sudden loud sounds unpleasant or shocking. The same can happen with some smells, temperature or light. Many believe that this is the result of unforeseen changes. Therefore, if a person with autism knows about previous changes, he copes better with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Development In Different Areas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A child with autism in different areas can develop in different ways. For example, his cognitive skills can develop rapidly, while social interaction and speech significantly lag behind. A child with autism, unlike peers, can not catch the ball thrown to him, but he knows far more words. Autism hinders harmonious development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having High Intelligence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also a form of autism, called Asperger’s syndrome. In this state, people tend to have intelligence above the norm, but they have certain difficulties in understanding and understanding speech. As a result, they become closed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="autism" /><summary type="html">Autism is a relatively new disorder, which is becoming more common. Its exact causes and methods of treatment are still a mystery. Experts believe that autism is the result of neurological disorders that affect the functioning of the brain, development, communication and social interaction skills. In other words, it is a disease of the nervous system.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What Are The Characteristics Of Autistic Kids?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-characteristics-of-autistic-kids/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Are The Characteristics Of Autistic Kids?" /><published>2018-09-29T10:14:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-09-29T10:14:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-characteristics-of-autistic-kids</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-characteristics-of-autistic-kids/">&lt;p&gt;Autism is a type of spectrum disorder that begins in the early childhood period but goes on whole life time and impairs social interaction and communication. If you ask ‘ why is autism called a spectrum disorder ‘, answer is that autism disorder symptoms may vary form person to person and it may have different types. Autism causes restricted and repetitous acts and prevents the development of brain.
&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2018/09/autism-12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;autism-12&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has My Child Asperger Syndrome Or Autism?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When indications of asperger syndrome and autism disorder overlap, doctors might not make a distinction between these two problems. Asperger syndrome is also a kind of disorder features as a light type of autism when we compare it with normal sort of autism that has the pervasive developmental character. Autistic kids often look like they are in their own world and don’t like talking too much. But kids have asperger syndrome are more communicative than autistic kids and when they talk about their field of interests they may talk exceedingly. Then the dialog begins to be one-sided. In austism speking skills develops very very slowly but in asperger syndrome the beginnig of speking and speking is normal like other kids don’t have any social problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Did Firstly Autism Name Begin To Be Used?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays autism problem is a common disorder which we hear its name too much. There has been an intensive interest in autism and autistic individulas for 20 years. As days pass, the technological developments continue and doctors discover the new aspects of these autistic kids. Because of the developments in medicine, the quality of autistic kids’ education is increasing. All these progresses day by day give hope to the parents have autistic kids. Autism firstly named by kid psychiatrist Leo Kanner in USA and he called this disorder as ‘Early Childhood Autism’.
&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2018/09/autistic-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;autistic-3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which Symptoms Do Autistic Kids Have? Is My Kid Autistic?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately we don’t have a particular psychiatric test which can diagnose autism disorder. It isn’t as easy as other disorders to make a diagnoses of autism. Psychiatrists listen what parents tell about their kids, they observe, evaluate the attitudes of the children and for psychiatrists to be able to diagnose autism, they often look for criterions listed below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disorders In Social Interaction (At Least Two Of These Symptoms Must Be Observed)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-The autistic kids have difficulty in social interaction. For instance autistic kids don’t like eye contact and their facial expressions, mimics and attitudes are dull.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-According to the kids’ level of development, the relations of autistic individuals with their peers are deficient in their social life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-They show high resistance while normal kids like sharing their succeses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-They are reluctant sharing their achievements and special interests and they show resistance to communicate other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Autism causes unwillingness to have social and emotional interaction. They don’t respond to other people like ordinary normal kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Psychiatrists might diagnose autism if they observe at least two symptoms among the problems listed above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication Problems (At Least One Of These Symptoms Must Be Observed)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Lateness of speaking skill development may be seen. In addition autistic kids don’t attempt to compensate this deficiency by the help of gestures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Autistic kids don’t try to begin conversation with their peers those have the ability of speaking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When a kid begins to talk with an autistic, autistic individual never continues talking and an insufficient attempt for continueing the chat is observed generally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experts might diagnose autism when they see at least one of these autism symptoms .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not Playing Imaginary And Symbolic Games (At Least One Of These Signs Must Be Observed)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-According to the level of development, austic kids never play imitation based and social games or they never play spontaneous and imaginary games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Repetitive, restricted and stereotyped activities, behaviours and points of interest are observed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Austic kids like spinning toys and objects and they are interested in abnormal activities. For instance when austics see a working washing machine or an object spinning, they focus on them intensively longtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Austic kids repeat insistently iterative movements, gestures and routines those don’t have a function or aim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experts might diagnose autism if they observe one of these autism symptoms .&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="autism" /><summary type="html">Autism is a type of spectrum disorder that begins in the early childhood period but goes on whole life time and impairs social interaction and communication. If you ask ‘ why is autism called a spectrum disorder ‘, answer is that autism disorder symptoms may vary form person to person and it may have different types. Autism causes restricted and repetitous acts and prevents the development of brain.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Education Of Children With Autism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/education-of-children-with-autism/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Education Of Children With Autism" /><published>2018-09-28T10:06:23+03:00</published><updated>2018-09-28T10:06:23+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/education-of-children-with-autism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/education-of-children-with-autism/">&lt;p&gt;The world around us is not percepted for all of the people the same way. Autistic children are one of those who percept the world a lot more different than others do. What we have to do in this case is try to find the wayof communication of our and their understanding. And for that the education of autistic children is a must.
&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2018/09/autism-11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;autism-11&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Classes about thoughts and feelings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recognizing and understanding thoughts and feelings, both one’s own and others, is often hard of children with autism, and it is necessary for successful communication. For example, we constantly change our behavior according to the non-verbal feedback that we receive from other people. We can continue the story if the other person is smiling, looking expectantly or showing other signs of genuine interest. On the other hand, if a person looks at the clock all the time, sighs, looks the other way, we, probably, will shorten our story. Children with autism often have difficulty in recognizing and understanding these non-verbal signals. Because of this, it is more difficult for them to modify their behavior to respond to the emotional and mental needs of others.&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2018/09/autism-child-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;autism-child-3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simplest activity about thoughts and feelings includes showing the child pictures with different expressions of emotions. Pictures can range from the most basic ones, such as happy, sad, angry or scared to more complex emotions, such as embarrassed, bashful, nervous or incredulous. Begin with a request to the child to show emotion, then ask to identify the child, what the character feels (“what does he feel?”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social Stories&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The method of social stories is often used in teaching social skills of children with disabilities. Social stories are an unobtrusive way to explain to children social concepts and rules in the form of a short history. This strategy can be used to train a variety of social and behavioral concepts, such as crossing the street, participating in the game and traveling out of town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Role Play / Behavioral Rehearsal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Role games and behavioral rehearsals are used, first of all, for teaching basic communication skills. This is an effective approach for teaching social skills, which allows for the positive practice of these skills. Role-playing games include playing situations or activities in a structured environment to try out in practice new skills and strategies or skills that were acquired earlier, in which the child has difficulty in using. Role-playing games can follow the script or be spontaneous. In the second case, the child is described a situation (for example, ask another child to play with him), but no specific scenario is given. For example, an autistic child may be given a question or a first sentence, but the rest of the conversation should be spontaneous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video modeling&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video modeling is, without a doubt, one of the most effective strategies for teaching social skills. Video modeling involves viewing a demonstration of some behavior on the video and then repeating the behavior of the model. In the video simulation can participate peers, adults or the child himself (video-samomodelirovanie). Video self-modeling can be used to acquire skills, improve the use of skills and reduce problem behavior. It combines a powerful learning tool for a child with autism (visual instructions) with an effective method of intervention (modeling).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intervention&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you have evaluated the social functioning and selected the skills for training, a distinction was drawn between the lack of mastery of the skill and the lack of use of the skill and chose the method of intervention, it’s time to start correcting. Social skills training should take place in different places and by different instructors. There is no “best” place for social skills training, although it is important to keep in mind that the goal of any socialization education is to enable the child to be socially successful with his peers in the natural environment. Essentially, if a child is taught social skills in the resource class of the school (or with the help of a private therapist), there must be a plan to transfer these skills from the resource class to the natural environment. Parents and teachers should look for opportunities to support and encourage skills that the child is taught in a resource class or correctional center.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="autism-education" /><summary type="html">The world around us is not percepted for all of the people the same way. Autistic children are one of those who percept the world a lot more different than others do. What we have to do in this case is try to find the wayof communication of our and their understanding. And for that the education of autistic children is a must.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Anger And Aggressıon In Chıldren Wıth Autısm</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/anger-and-aggression-in-children-with-autism/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Anger And Aggressıon In Chıldren Wıth Autısm" /><published>2018-09-27T08:23:54+03:00</published><updated>2018-09-27T08:23:54+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/anger-and-aggression-in-children-with-autism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/anger-and-aggression-in-children-with-autism/">&lt;p&gt;Almost all of the kids with autism show agressive symptoms and have a hard time controlling their anger. To reduce agression in autistic to minimum, some important stp need to be taken. And he best one of them is starting a treatment of your child. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With such a variety of treatments for autism, understanding which method is right for your child can be quite a challenge. It also complicates the situation and the fact that you can hear different and sometimes even contradictory responses from parents and doctors. You need to take into account that there is no single method of treatment that will work for everyone, and this must be taken into account when drawing up a treatment plan for your child. Everyone with ADS is unique, with its strengths and weaknesses.
&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2018/09/autism--.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;autism--&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Treatment Plan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good treatment plan should:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be based on your child’s interests&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be a clear plan&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Include tasks consisting of a number of simple steps&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Actively include your child in highly structured activities&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Assuming regular reinforcement of behavior&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Assume the participation of parents&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions To Ask When Making A Treatment Plan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The treatment of child with autism must be adapted according to his individual needs. No one knows your child better than you, so you need to check that these needs are met. To make this easier, ask yourself these questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What are the strengths of your child?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What are the weaknesses of your child?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What behavior causes the most difficulties?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What are your child’s important skills?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How is it easier for your child to learn (using visual stimuli, auditory or physical)?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What gives your child pleasure, and how can this be used in treatment?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, finally, always remember that no matter what treatment plan was chosen, your participation is crucial to success. You can help your child get the maximum effect from the treatment if you work closely with the team of therapists and continue to implement therapy at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2018/09/autism-child-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;autism-child-2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Choice Of A Method Of Treatment Of Autism&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a huge number of different methods and approaches to treating autism. Some of them are aimed at eliminating problem behavior, building communication and social skills, while others are more focused on problems of sensory integration, motor skills, emotional problems and food sensitivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In connection with the existence of such a wide choice, it is extremely important to conduct your own research, talk with experts and find out all the questions that interest you. But keep in mind that you do not need to choose only one treatment method. Often, a combined treatment approach is required that can take advantage of the various therapies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, autism treatment programs include behavioral therapy, speech therapy, game therapy, occupational therapy and nutritional therapy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find Help And Support&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking care of a child with ADS can require you a lot of energy and time. There will be days when you can feel exhausted, desperate and tense. Raising children is not always easy, but raising a child with features is an even more difficult task. To be a better parent, it’s important to take care of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Autism Support Groups&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; A support group is an opportunity to meet other families with the same difficulties as you. Parents can share information, get advice and provide emotional support to each other. Even just being with others “in the same boat” and sharing experience, one can cope with the feeling of “isolation” that parents often experience when they receive a diagnosis of ADS from their child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Temporary Care&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each parent needs time for rest. And for the parents of a special child, this is especially true. A temporary nanny can take care of the child for a short time, giving you a rest for several hours, days or even weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individual, Marital Or Family Counseling&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; If you experience stress, anxiety and depression, you can visit the doctor yourself. Therapy is a place where you can frankly talk about all of yours. Spousal or family counseling can also help resolve problems in the relationship of spouses and other family members.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="autism" /><summary type="html">Almost all of the kids with autism show agressive symptoms and have a hard time controlling their anger. To reduce agression in autistic to minimum, some important stp need to be taken. And he best one of them is starting a treatment of your child. </summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What Are The Reasons Of Autism?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-reasons-of-autism/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Are The Reasons Of Autism?" /><published>2018-09-26T08:12:28+03:00</published><updated>2018-09-26T08:12:28+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-reasons-of-autism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-reasons-of-autism/">&lt;p&gt;Autism is called autism spectrum disorder which generally appears at the age of 3 years old and continues lifelong. Social interaction problems, verbal and non-verbal problems, repetitious behaviors, limited concerns are seen in autism which is a complex progressional disorder. If parents pay attention to simle signs, it is easily diagnosed and after diagnosis when experts apply a good rehabilitation to the baby, the affects of the disorder might be decreased significantly. In the period of the pregnancy folic acid usage decreases the developments of the autism risk highly. Nowadays one of 110 children are in the effect of this disorder and so many families are influenced by autism. Till in the middle of 21th century autism disorder hadn’t had even a name.
&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2018/09/autism-children.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;autism-children&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Causes Autism?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reasons of autism hasn’t been precisely discovered yet. There isn’t only one reason of autism. Nowadays it is know that autism has many reasons. The brain cells of autistic individuals work differently. Between brain cells the chemical transmitters have deficiency or surplus and some of the genetic illnesses are among the causes of autism .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Genetic Factors Play İmportant Role&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Genetic factors plays an important role in the causes of autism. The studies on twins and relatives verify this important role. But studies shows that genetic is not the only reason of autism. If genetic is the only reason of autism both of all identical twins had autism when one of the twins has autism. But the state isn’t always like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also Environmental Factors Are Effective&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also the studies show that environmental factors have a role in autism. Between prenatal and post-natal factors and autism, dramatical relations have been detected. Studies show that individuals have genetically tendency to autism have the risk of having problem at the period of birth highly. Additionaly it is known that at the period of pregnancy having rubella problem is effective on autism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Arise Of Autism With Rates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays it is absolutely known that the reason of autism isn’t because of only one factor. Autism is a disorder affected by more than one factor which is a reasonably complex problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers agree that males are four times more likely to be autistic than females. Seventy percent of autistic individuals have mental retardation. Thirty percent of them are normal and ten percent of this rate has superior intelligence. Epilepsy, attention deficit disorders with hyperactivity or mood disorders are seen with autism commonly. One of three autistics have the epileptic risks.
&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2018/09/autism-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;autism-1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Symptoms Of Autism&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-The eye contact is restricted&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-They have restricted interests&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-They don’t respond when you call their name&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They might be hyperactive or stagnant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Some of the autistic children don’t like physical contact&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-They look like they live in their own world&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-They don’t have imitation ability or this ability is restricted&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Speaking skill develops very slowly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Even if they develop speaking skill, they don’t speak to communicate commonly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-They repeat what is said to them again and again&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Their pronoun usage skills are restricted&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-They speak mechanically or with a monotonous voice tone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-They have order obsession&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-They don’t play imaginary games or they continuously play the same games&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But autism symptoms vary or a kid might have a few of these signs but another autistic kid might have all the symtoms. Generally autistic kids have difficulty in communicating with other kids and they like spinning toys or objects. And sometimes they look at spinning objects very carefully.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="autism" /><summary type="html">Autism is called autism spectrum disorder which generally appears at the age of 3 years old and continues lifelong. Social interaction problems, verbal and non-verbal problems, repetitious behaviors, limited concerns are seen in autism which is a complex progressional disorder. If parents pay attention to simle signs, it is easily diagnosed and after diagnosis when experts apply a good rehabilitation to the baby, the affects of the disorder might be decreased significantly. In the period of the pregnancy folic acid usage decreases the developments of the autism risk highly. Nowadays one of 110 children are in the effect of this disorder and so many families are influenced by autism. Till in the middle of 21th century autism disorder hadn’t had even a name.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tips To Handle Autism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tips-to-handle-autism/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tips To Handle Autism" /><published>2018-09-25T09:11:43+03:00</published><updated>2018-09-25T09:11:43+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tips-to-handle-autism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tips-to-handle-autism/">&lt;p&gt;For parents, teachers and friends of an autistic struggling with this disorder is about as hard as it is to the children with autism. The following tips will help to ease everyday household life, both for parents and their children.
&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2018/09/autism.Jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;autism&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be Consistent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Children with autism take time to adapt skills learned in one environment, to other conditions, including the home environment. For example, your child can use sign language for communication in school, but will not think that he can also communicate at home. Creating a sequence in your child’s environment is the best way to consolidate your skills. Find out what therapists are working with the child at the moment, and do it at home. Study the possibility of conducting therapy in different places to stimulate your child to use the knowledge gained in a different environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow The Schedule&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Children with autism tend to feel more comfortable if they have a well-structured schedule. Set a schedule indicating the exact time for eating, therapy, school and sleep. Try to keep changes in the schedule to a minimum. If the change is unavoidable, prepare the child in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encourage Good Behavior&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Positive strengthening can significantly help you in progress, so make every effort to find something for which you can encourage the child. Praise children when they act appropriately or use a new skill, while clearly articulating what you praise the child for. In addition, look for other ways to encourage them for good behavior, for example, to give a sticker or allow them to play with your favorite toy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create A Home Security Zone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give the child space in your home, where he can relax, feel protected and be safe. The boundaries should be set so that the child can understand them. You can use visual markers (colored tapes or the zones indicated by pictures / photos). You should be sure that the allocated area is really safe for your child, especially if he is prone to hysterics or self-aggression.
&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2018/09/autism-childrens-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;autism-childrens-1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find The Nonverbal Mode Of Communication&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Establishing communication with an autistic child can be a challenge, but you do not need to talk for communication. You already communicate with your child - the way you look at it, touch it, the tone of your voice and the language of your body - all this is also communication. And your child also communicates with you, even if he never expresses it in words. You just need to learn this language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find Out The Reason For His Hysterics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; It is quite natural for any child to get upset because he is not understood or ignored. If you encounter such a situation, then most likely the reason is that you do not catch his non-verbal signals. Having arranged a tantrum, the child tries to attract your attention and express his disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make Time For Fun&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The child with ADS is still a child. Both the child and his parents need to enjoy life and try not to turn it solely into therapy. Schedule time for games for the period of maximum activity of the child. Find ways to have fun together, think about what makes a child smile, laugh and lets him “open up.” Your child will enjoy such moments, especially when he realizes that this is not related to therapy or training.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="autism" /><summary type="html">For parents, teachers and friends of an autistic struggling with this disorder is about as hard as it is to the children with autism. The following tips will help to ease everyday household life, both for parents and their children.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Problems Autıstıc Chıldren Face Wıth</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/problems-autistic-children-face-with/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Problems Autıstıc Chıldren Face Wıth" /><published>2018-09-24T08:50:45+03:00</published><updated>2018-09-24T08:50:45+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/problems-autistic-children-face-with</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/problems-autistic-children-face-with/">&lt;p&gt;Most specialists and autistic parents know about the main differences in the experience of autistic people. However, autistics have other differences, which often turn into serious problems, because the surrounding people do not know about the existence of these differences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These, not so well-known features, although they can be considered problems on their own, become even more difficult, because society does not know about them, and does not provide support in connection with them. As always in such cases, the solution is to recognize these differences and try to build a community in which they will become just differences and not huge problems (yes, it is not always possible, but still it is possible and should try to do it) .
&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2018/09/autism-10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;autism-10&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Erroneous assumptions about competence
One of the main problems that autistics face is erroneous assumptions about which specific tasks they will find themselves in, and in which they do not. It’s normal to recognize that a person does something well, but something does not work out well, if you have evidence to support this opinion. It is quite another matter when you assume the presence or absence of a certain ability, proceeding from some completely extraneous feature of a person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A characteristic feature of autism is that autistics can have very developed abilities in some areas and at the same time very big problems in others. Abilities of autistics, as a rule, represent a series of mountain peaks and deep ravines, even if it is a question of skills that are considered to be “related” to each other. For example, an autist can very well formulate his thoughts in writing, but at the same time he can have very serious problems with oral speech.
&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2018/09/autism-child-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;autism-child-1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initiating Actions
The problem with initiation of actions is one of the most little known difficulties in autism. Of course, like any differences in autism, this problem is not universal, and some autistics do not experience problems with initiation of movements or communication. However, very often people around autists believe that if an autist does not enter into communication with others, then he himself decided not to communicate with anyone. They do not think that he is simply incapable of initiating the movements and communication that are necessary for communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Problems with initiation of actions penetrate into all possible areas of life. Autistic people (note, not all autistics have these features) have difficulty in starting a conversation in order to speak in a group of people to tell someone about their problems (for example, it may be difficult for a person to talk to a doctor about their stomach upset ), to ask for help, or simply to start certain actions necessary in everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personal care
Taking care of yourself is another area that is especially difficult for many autistics. Some of us are unable to look “clean and tidy”, regardless of the efforts made, while others find it useless even to try. Problems with taking care of yourself can include difficulties with regular showering or bathing, painful sensations when trying to wash your hair, difficulties with dental care, problems with washing, and many others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food and Nutrition
Many autistics have problems with eating and eating. For most of them, the body weight is either significantly lower or significantly above normal.  They may have problems with cooking and even with such a simple task as eating food already prepared for them. Very often they are extremely picky eaters, and for them it is not only difficult, but it is impossible to eat dishes that cause unpleasant sensory sensations (for example, they may not be able to eat dishes in which different foods are mixed).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Autistic people find it very difficult to understand when and how much food should be eaten. While these problems can be caused (or aggravated) by depression or illness, autism itself can be the cause. For example, some autistic people simply do not have reliable feelings of “hunger” or “thirst.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Health care
The health system is often unavailable to autistics, even if they have no problems with poverty or lack of health insurance, which is not uncommon. It may be very difficult to enroll to a doctor (“Do I need a specialist or a therapist?”, “Do I need to tell a doctor about autism?”, “What will they ask me about?”). No less problems await during the visit to the doctor, as well as when filling out various forms or following the procedures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this is only part of the problems of health care of autistic people. It seems that they perceive the symptoms differently than the neurotypics. Some of them do not mention the symptom, unless the doctor asks about it directly. Many of autists confuse internal sensations, and it may be difficult for them to understand that we are sick. &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="autism" /><summary type="html">Most specialists and autistic parents know about the main differences in the experience of autistic people. However, autistics have other differences, which often turn into serious problems, because the surrounding people do not know about the existence of these differences.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Caring For An Autistic Child</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/caring-for-an-autistic-child/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Caring For An Autistic Child" /><published>2018-09-22T20:01:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-09-22T20:01:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/caring-for-an-autistic-child</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/caring-for-an-autistic-child/">&lt;p&gt;What rules should be adhered to the families of autistic children so that it can develop and function normally in society?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Children with autism need to communicate even more than their peers are healthy. Families with a child with autism are always special, as a lot of physical and psychological stress falls on all family members. First of all, one adult family member (most often a mother) must stay with the child all the time to provide him with proper care and to be able to constantly engage in socialization and development.
 &lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2018/09/autism-9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;autism-9&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Are The Rules Of Life With An Autistic Child?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Activities With The Autist &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ensure that a child with autism can function normally in the community, it is necessary to constantly work with him. The child’s education program should be designed by a specialist so that the child can do what he really enjoys and cares, and parents can help him cope with the training that will help the child to prove himself in later life. Many autistics, with whom they persevered in childhood, later became successful programmers, artists, writers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Clear Regime Of The Day&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To a child with autism, he can normally feel, it is necessary to make for him a clear regime of the day. Then take a closer look at whether the child will be able to follow this regime, and correct it. It must be borne in mind that autistic children are sensitive to even the slightest changes not only in the daily routine, but even in the arrangement of things. Therefore, you should minimize any changes in the daily routine in the future. ,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do Not Interrupt Employment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All family life should be subordinated to the need for regular classes with the child. Classes should not be interrupted for any reason, you can slightly shorten, in case of emergency, but not interrupt. Progress is achieved by hard and constant labor, but regression occurs quickly. If there is an opportunity to attend a correctional school, where, in addition to special sessions with teachers and psychologists, you can communicate with other kids and their families - it’s good, as it gives an incentive not only to the child, but also to the parents.
&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2018/09/autism-autism-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;autism-autism-3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communicating With An Autistic Child&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you know, autistic children can not endure touch, but for the development of the child’s psyche they are simply necessary, so a light massage before bedtime can help.  At the time of conception, the risk of developing autism in a child depends on the child. Such a child needs to communicate as much as possible, although the behavior and the detached view can create an impression that the child does not want communication at all. However, remember that autistic children need to communicate even more than healthy peers. But we note that their peculiarity is the need for periodic seclusion, so sometimes let the child be alone with them. Arrange for the child a place where he can be alone, and nobody will touch him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food Intolerance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Children with autism are often prone to intolerance to certain foods. Therefore, often children with autism are recommended a special diet with a restriction of products rich in casein and gluten, as well as sweet. However, watch the child to determine which foods he has a negative reaction to. Perhaps for him to develop another diet. In any case, it is worth giving a child multivitamins. Following these rules of life with a child suffering from autism, you can help him and yourself to cope with the difficult task of socialization of the child, and also contribute to his psychological development.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="autism" /><summary type="html">What rules should be adhered to the families of autistic children so that it can develop and function normally in society?</summary></entry></feed>